GUSTAVO HENRIQUE

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

LINKEDIN | GITHUB avoguga@gmail.com (82) 99306-3333 Maceió/AL

OBJECTIVE

Proactive and self-taught professional, with excellent critical thinking skills and used to working in challenging environments. That brings experience with web development using React JS, Vue and Angular and still has an affinity for creating REST APIs with Java, Python and NodeJS. For mobile development has experience with React Native. Currently, the language in which he has been specializing is JavaScript, conducting studies and working with its most diverse concepts. Wants to build a solid career in Software Development, focusing on technical specialization, believes that opportunities can leverage the achievement of goals.

EXPERIENCE

Hand Talk

Front-End Developer | March 2022 - Currently

At Hand Talk, I'm responsible for maintaining the LIBRAS Translator Plugin, where I use ReactJS and typescript to work on refactorings and improvements in the product code, in addition to creating new features, creating reusable components and using good accessibility practices. I also acted in the creation and implementation of the company's Design System. Where I was in charge of creating test environments in the most diverse web environments, using Ruby, NodeJs, NextJS and NuxtJS to test the product on customer sites; Still implementing standards, improvements, and create documentation on the tests performed, in addition to technically evaluating problems and bugs on customer sites, for the optimal use of the product.

Vérttice Gerenciamento de Riscos

Front-End Developer | July 2021 – August 2021

I was responsible for the maintenance of the Valida system, where I could learn to create reusable components using VueJS. Integrated the system with the API made in Symphony PHP and performed the refactoring of the application's main registration and query system, in addition to having to interact with user systems for validating and validating CPFs, and validating documents through RESTful APIs. I had great experience with Scrum and the Taiga tool, open source project management software that allowed me to carry out work efficiently using agile frameworks such as Scrum and Kanban.

Mesha Tecnologia

Front-End Developer | March 2021 – May 2021

At Mesha, I was in charge of creating components for the onboarding of the <u>Senai Play</u> project, where I had to use tools such as: Angular 8, to build reusable components and features for the application, Shepherd JS, the library used to carry out onboardings, pre -CSS processors, such as SASS and GitLab: For project versioning.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

- Information Systems Centro de Estudos Superiores de Maceió (CESMAC)
 Graduation | 2023
- Chemistry Technician Instituto Federal de Alagoas (IFAL)
 Integrated High School | 2019

PROJECTS

 <u>Static App</u> - Application for determination of internal efforts and vertical displacement in linear structural elements

The application was built together with FAPEAL scholarship holders from the engineering course at Centro Universitário CESMAC in order to determine the internal forces and vertical displacement in static linear structural elements in order to assist in the teaching-learning process in the area of structures.

Toolkit de Acessibilidade

Accessibility toolkit, currently performs site reading, spacing and font size increase, I plan to turn it into a node package and make it available for free.

Jogo da Velha - Published on Google Store

Tic-tac-toe game that was developed using React Native and simple logic. The application was initially developed with the aim of teaching people to develop mobile applications for beginners in programming.

EXTRACURRICULAR COURSES

Web Accessibility – Alura

6 hours | July 2022

Web Performance I: Optimizing the Frontend - Alura

20 hours | November 2022

Handoff: documenting project delivery – Alura

3 hours | November 2022

Quality Assurance: test plan and bug management – Alura

15 hours | February 2022

React: Abstracting CSS with Styled Components – Alura

2,5 hours | January 2022

Angular & NodeJS – Maximillian Schwarzmuller

85 hours | July 2021

React e TypeScript: developing a full dashboard – Rodrigo Gonçalves Santana

36 hour | April 2021

Vue JS 2 The Complete Guide – Cod3r Courses

10 hour | February 2021